It is so wonderful for your Mother to see so many
برای مادرتان خیلی فوق‌العاده است که ببیند
beautiful Sahaja yogis assembled together,
این همه ساهاجایوگی‌ زیبا، یک‌جا،
on this day of Sahasrara.
در این روز سحسرار گرد هم آمده‌اند.
I think the first era of Sahaja Yoga has ended now,
به نظر من، هم اکنون اولین دوران ساهاجایوگا پایان یافته
and new has started.
و دوره جدید شروع شده است.
In the first era of Sahaja Yoga,
در دوران اول ساهاجایوگا،
the starting point was first the opening of the Sahasrara.
نقطه آغازین، در ابتدا باز شدن سحسرارا بود
And gradually –
و به تدریج...
and gradually moving towards the completion,
و به تدریج حرکت به سوی کمال،
I find there are so many who are great Sahaja yogis today.
من می‌بینم امروز تعداد زیادی ساهاجایوگی‌های عالی وجود دارند.
It is a very natural process of growth
این روندی بسیار طبیعی در رشد است
that you have gone through.
که شما طی کرده‌اید.
The first one was, we can say,
مرحله اول، می‌شود گفت،
is just the awakening of the Kundalini,
فقط بیداری کندالینی بود
and piercing the fontanel bone area.
و گشودن استخوان ملاج سر.
As you see on top of your head these bandhans,
همان‌طور که در بالای سرتان این بندن‌ها را می‌بینید،
that's how you too have in your head, same way.
در سرتان هم به همان شکل بندن دارید
And you have the chakras same way built in,
و چاکراها هم در سحسرارای شما به همین شکل
in your Sahasrara.
جاسازی شده‌اند.
So in the first era of Sahaja Yoga we have awakened
پس در اولین دوران ساهاجایوگا،
the deities in your centers,
ما دیتی‌ها را در چاکراهای شما بیدار کرده‌ایم،
in the medulla oblongata and also in the brain.
در بصل النخاع و نیز در مغز.
But now the time has come for us to spread it
ولی الان برای ما، زمان آن رسیده که ساهاجایوگا را
on a horizontal level.
در سطح افقی گسترش دهیم،
And to move it on the horizontal level,
و برای پیشبرد آن در سطح افقی،
we have to understand how to go about it.
باید بفهمیم چطور به این کار بپردازیم.
Like the seven colors of the rainbow,
همچون هفت رنگ رنگین کمان،
we have got seven colors of the light of these centers,
ما هفت رنگ نور مربوط به این مراکز،
of the chakras.
یا چاکراها را داریم.
And when we start it from the back,
و وقتی از پشت شروع کنیم،
from the Mooladhara, bringing it up to the,
از مولادهارا، آن را تا بالا به این سمت،
this side, Agnya, then it is placed in a different order,
به اگنیا بیاوریم، آن وقت اگر به دقت توجه کنید
if you see it clearly.
می‌بینید به ترتیب دیگری قرار می‌گیرد.
I mean to say that in the Sahasrara,
منظورم آن است که در سحسرارا
because it's a concave replacement,
به دلیل گنبدی شکل بودنش،
is important to understand that the center
مهم است بدانیم که مرکز
of the fontanel bone area corresponds to our heart.
این ملاج سر، بر قلب ما منطبق می‌شود.
So heart is the pivotal point for the second era now.
بنابراین الان قلب، نقطه‌ای کلیدی‌ برای دومین دوران ماست.
I hope you understand what I mean.
امیدوارم متوجه منظورم بشوید.
So if you have to place your attention to Sahasrara,
پس اگر باید توجه خودتان را بر سحسرارا بگذارید،
first thing you have to do is to pay attention to your heart.
اولین کاری که باید بکنید آن است که توجهتان را به قلبتان معطوف کنید.
In the Sahasrara, the Heart Chakra and the heart itself,
در سحسرارا، چاکرای قلب و خود قلب،
the Atma, coincide.
یعنی روح بر هم منطبق می‌شوند.
Means the Jagadamba becomes one with the heart –
بدین معنی که جاگادامبا با قلب یکی می‌شود،
that is the Atma.
که روح است.
So we see that here the yoga takes place.
پس می‌بینیم اینجا یوگا اتفاق می‌افتد.
At this point of time it is very important to understand
در این برهه از زمان، دریافت این مطلب بسیار مهم است
that we have to take a bigger step.
که ما باید قدمی بزرگتر برداریم.
The whole Sahasrara moves in this way,
کل سحسرارا به این شکل حرکت می‌کند.
all these chakras throw their lights in this way,
تمامی این چاکراها به این شکل نورافشانی می‌کنند،
in a clockwise manner; and this axis is the heart.
به شکل ساعتگرد؛ و محور، قلب است.
So the essence of all the religions, of all the prophets,
بنابراین جوهره تمام مذاهب، تمام پیامبران،
of all the incarnations is compassion,
تمام اینکارنیشن‌ها محبت است
and it’s placed in this Chakra of Heart.
و در این چاکرای قلب قرار دارد.
Thus we understand that in the second era now,
بدین ترتیب متوجه می‌شویم که اکنون در دوره دوم،
we have to have compassion.
باید محبت داشته باشیم.
Is the manifestation now of the compassion.
الان دوره تجلی محبت است.
If God Almighty had no compassion,
اگر خداوند متعال محبت نداشت،
He would not have created this great universe.
این عالم عظیم را نمی‌آفرید.
Actually His Power, or the Adi Shakti,
در واقع قدرت او یا آدی شاکتی،
is the embodiment of His compassion.
محبت خداوند است که به جسم درآمده
And this compassion has brought forth all the evolution
و این محبت باعث جلوبردن کل تکامل
to human level, and even your emancipation as Sahaja yogis.
تا حد انسان و حتی رستگاری شما به عنوان یک ساهاجایوگی شده است
And compassion is always completely covered
و محبت همیشه کاملا مملو
with forgiveness.
از بخشش است.
So you can see, the Trinity meets at this point.
بنابراین می‌توانید ببینید که عوامل تثلیث در این نقطه به هم می‌رسند.
The Son of God is forgiveness,
پسر خداوند بخشش است،
is the embodiment of forgiveness.
مظهر بخشش است.
So the God Almighty who is the witness,
بنابراین، خداوند که همان شاهد است،
the Mother who is the compassion
مادر که همان محبت است
and the Child who is the forgiveness,
و بچه که همان بخشش است
all of them meet at Heart Chakra, in the Sahasrara.
تمام آنها در چاکرای قلب، در سحسرارا به هم می‌رسند.
Now, one must learn how to improve Sahasrara itself.
حالا ما باید یاد بگیریم که چطور خود سحسرارا را بهبود بخشیم.
You know the presiding deity of the Sahasrara very well.
شما دیتی مقیم سحسرارا را خیلی خوب می‌شناسید.
Now the place of Sahasrara is in your head,
حال محل سحسرارا در سر شما قرار دارد،
as you think it to be,
که شما هم فکر می‌کنید همین است،
but it’s just the center of the whole universe.
ولی سحسرارا درست مرکز کل عالم است.
To develop this, you have to pay attention
برای رسیدن به این، شما باید به چاکرای قلب
to your Heart Chakra in the fontanel bone area.
در محل ملاج سر توجه کنید.
If you pay attention to the fontanel bone area,
اگر به محل ملاج سر توجه کنید،
then there you must establish the deity.
آن وقت، آنجا، شما باید دیتی آن را تثبیت کنید.
But this deity has to be first established into the heart.
ولی این دیتی ابتدا باید در قلب تثبیت شود.
Now you are very lucky people that you have the deity
حالا شما آدم‌های بسیار خوشبختی هستید که دیتی را
in person with you.
شخصا در کنارتان دارید.
The people who got realization before I came on this Earth
کسانی که پیش از آمدن من به زمین خودآگاهی گرفتند،
had to imagine the deities,
باید دیتی‌ها را تصور می‌کردند
and in that imagination they were never perfect.
و آنها در این تصورکردنشان هیچ وقت کامل نبودند.
But as they say that at Sahasrara She is Mahamaya –
ولی گفته می‌شود که: "در سحسرارا او ماهامایا است"
that is how it is described –
و او بدین شکل توصیف می‌شود.
so if you also see the person,
بنابراین شما هم اگر شخص او را ببینید،
you may not be knowing fully that person
شاید نتوانید او را کاملا بشناسید
or in the perfect way or a complete way,
یا به شکلی کامل یا به شکلی جامع،
because Mahamaya Shakti is much greater
چون ماهامایا شاکتی بسیار بزرگتر از
than your imagination.
حد تصور شماست.
That is why one has to surrender.
برای همین است که باید تسلیم شد.
With your limited imagination of brain,
با تصور محدود مغزتان،
one cannot see the deity.
نمی‌توانید دیتی را ببینید.
Also it is said She is Bhakti Gamya:
و نیز گفته می‌شود که او بْهاکتی گامیا است؛
you can know through bhakti, through devotion.
شما می‌توانید او را به کمک بْهاکتی، به کمک سرسپردگی بشناسید.
So the devotion has to be there,
بنابراین سرسپردگی باید وجود داشته باشد؛
but the devotion has to be a very clean devotion,
ولی سرسپردگی باید از نوع بسیار پاک آن باشد،
in the sense there should be no malice in the heart.
به این معنی که هیچ بداندیشی در قلب نباشد،
Heart should be clean.
قلب باید پاک باشد.
Heart, to keep it clean is very difficult.
پاک نگه داشتن قلب بسیار مشکل است.
Always human beings have a relative understanding of
همواره انسان‌ها یک فهم نسبی
of reality,
از حقیقت دارند،
but reality is absolute.
ولی حقیقت مطلق است.
So to achieve that, one has to get rid of all
بنابراین برای رسیدن به آن، شخص باید
the other kind of impurities that are within the heart.
از انواع دیگر ناپاکی‌ها که درون قلب است خلاص شود.
So in the beginning we try to achieve our realization,
پس ابتدا ما سعی می‌کنیم که به خودآگاهی خودمان برسیم،
not with very clean heart.
نه با قلبی بسیار پاک.
At that time we had lots of attachments,
آن موقع ما وابستگی‌های زیادی داشتیم،
we were identified with false things.
ما با چیزهایی دروغین خود را یکی می‌دانستیم
And also we thought by getting realization
و نیز فکر می‌کردیم که با گرفتن خودآگاهی،
we’ll become very powerful people.
افراد بسیار قدرتمندی خواهیم شد.
After realization also,
بعد از خودآگاهی هم،
we started indulging into petty things.
به مسائل بی‌اهمیت پرداختیم.
We started asking for favors for our relations, friends,
شروع به درخواست برای وابستگانمان، دوستانمان،
mothers, sisters;
مادرانمان و خواهرانمان کردیم.
and the women thought of their husbands
و زنان به فکر شوهرانشان
and their brothers, children.
و برادرانشان و بچه‌هایشان بودند.
They all asked for the blessings of all those
آنها همه طلب رحمت داشتند برای کسانی که
with whom they were entangled.
زندگی‌شان با آنها گره خورده بود.
All this entanglement you got over, I know, very soon.
می‌دانم که شما هم خیلی سریع از این گره‌ها رها شدید.
Now the job of a Avatara is such
حالا کار یک آواتارا چنین است
that He has to fulfill the desires of His bhaktas.
که او باید آرزوهای بْهاکتاهایش را برآورده کند.
The job of an Avatara is such that He has to fulfill
کار یک آواتارا چنین است که او باید
the desires of His bhaktas, His disciples.
آرزوهای بْهاکتاهایش، شاگردانش را برآورده کند.
For example, Shri Krishna was asked by gopis that
برای مثال گوپی‌ها از شری کریشنا می‌خواهند که:
“we want You to be with us,
"ما می‌خواهیم با ما باشی،
individually with every one of us.”
با هر کدام از ما به تنهایی."
So He divided Himself into many Krishnas,
برای همین او خودش را به کریشناهای زیادی تقسیم کرد
and He was with every one of them.
و با هر کدام از آنها به سر برد.
But that was a very divine desire, I think;
ولی به نظرم، آن آرزویی بسیار الهی بود؛
that was a very divine desire of the gopis.
آن آرزوی بسیار الهی گوپی‌ها بود.
But when you asked Me about your brothers, sisters,
اما وقتی شما از من برای برادرها، خواهرها،
mothers, fathers, I tried to do that,
مادرها و پدرهایتان چیزی می‌خواهید، من سعی می‌کنم
whatever was possible.
تا سرحدامکان آن کارها را انجام دهم.
Also the kshema that you asked for,
و نیز آن کْشِمایی که درخواست کردید،
ashrams you asked for,
اشرام‌هایی که درخواست کردید،
all the things that you needed,
تمام چیزهایی که نیاز داشتید،
was there for your desire to be fulfilled.
داده شد تا خواسته‌های شما برآورده شود.
So at the Krishna's level it was
بنابراین در مرحله کریشنا،
"Yoga kshemam vahamyaham."
این "یوگا-کشما-واهامیام" را داشتیم،
So the kshema was looked after at Krishna's level,
یعنی در مرحله کریشنا، به "کْشِما" رسیدگی شد،
because it was promised.
چون این وعده داده شده بود.
But what next, in the new era that has to come?
ولی بعد از آن، در دوران جدیدی که قرار است بیاید چه؟
As you have now good families, good ashrams,
حالا که شما خانواده‌های خوب، اشرام‌های خوب
good jobs, everyone is happy, let us think of the next era.
و شغل‌های خوب دارید، همه خوشحال هستند. بیایید به دوره بعد فکر کنیم.
Next era is of compassion, as I told you.
دوره بعدی دوره مهربانی است، همان‌طور که به شما گفتم.
But any one of the chakras are weak in you still;
ولی اگر هر کدام از این چاکراها هنوز در شما ضعیف باشد،
the light that becomes white because of the seven colors
نوری که به خاطر هفت رنگ سفید می‌شود،
may dim out, or may be defective.
ممکن است کم نور و ضعیف شود یا دچار اشکال گردد.
So, all the chakras that are within us
بنابراین باید مراقب تمام چاکراهایی که
are to be looked after.
در ما هستند بود.
To pay attention to every chakra, and put compassion,
توجه کردن به هر چاکرا، مهر ورزیدن به آن
the feeling of compassion on these chakras.
و احساس محبت برای این چاکراها.
Now let us take the Chakra of Shri Ganesh.
حالا بیایید چاکرای شری گانش را در نظر بگیریم.
You pay attention to Shri Ganesha and
شما به شری گانشا توجه می‌کنید
establish Him through your thought –
و او را از راه افکارتان تثبیت می‌کنید،
because now your thought is divine –
چون حالا افکار شما الهی هستند،
in the Mooladhara Chakra, with great respect.
در چاکرای مولادهارا با احترامی فوق‌العاده.
Here now, you have to know that in the first era
حالا اینجا شما باید بدانید که در اولین دوره ساهاجایوگا،
of Sahaja Yoga I could not have talked of these things to
من نمی‌توانستم
of these things to you, of …
از این چیزها به شما بگویم، از...
This is much subtler doing, subtler work.
این عملی بسیار ظریف‌تر و کاری بسیار ظریف‌تر است.
Now put your feeling on that chakra.
حالا احساساتتان را بر آن چاکرا بگذارید،
Chakra is the pradesha, is the country,
چاکرا پْرادِشا است، کشور است
and the king is Shri Ganesh.
و پادشاه شری گانشا است
And that's the country.
و آن کشور است.
Now when you put your attention onto that chakra,
حالا وقتی توجهتان را بر آن چاکرا می‌گذارید،
put your feelings towards Him,
احساساتتان را به سمت او بگذارید،
of feeling of love and adoration to Him, to begin with.
اول از همه احساس عشق و ستایش نسبت به او را؛
And then to manifest compassion,
و بعد برای این که محبت خود را ابراز کنید،
you have to ask nothing but one thing,
نیازی نیست چیزی بگویید جز این که:
that "O God of Innocence, give innocence
"ای خدای معصومیت،
to all the people of the world."
به تمام مردم جهان، پاکی عطا فرمایید."
But first you have to be innocent to ask that;
ولی قبل از هر چیز، شما باید پاک باشید تا این تقاضا را بکنید.
otherwise it is unauthorized asking, or you can say,
در غیر این صورت این یک تقاضای غیر مجاز است یا می‌شود گفت
you have no right to ask.
شما اجازه چنین تقاضایی را ندارید.
So to understand innocence
بنابراین برای درک پاکی،
you should try to understand yourself,
شما باید سعی کنید خودتان را درک کنید،
how your mind is working.
این که چطور ذهنتان دارد کار می‌کند.
When you, say, look at anyone, do you feel that you
مثلا وقتی شما به کسی نگاه می‌کنید،
should possess that person?
آیا احساس می‌کنید که باید آن شخص را در تملک خود بگیرید؟
Do you feel unduly attracted, or something base feeling
آیا احساس می کنید که بی‌جهت مجذوب او می‌شوید یا احساسات سطح پایینی
comes into your mind?
به ذهن شما می‌آید؟
For an innocent person,
برای شخصی معصوم،
a beautiful person, or a woman,
وقتی که او فردی زیبا را می‌بیند، یا یک زن
or a beautiful scene or a beautiful creation,
یا منظره‌ای زیبا یا یک خلقت زیبا را،
the first thing should happen that he becomes thoughtless –
اولین چیزی که باید برای او اتفاق بیفتد آن است که بی‌فکر ‌شود،
there’s no thought.
هیچ فکری وجود نداشته باشد.
So if there is no thought, there's no question
پس اگر هیچ فکری نباشد، دیگر جایی
of having any expression of possessiveness
برای ابراز حس تملک
or any kind of a baser feeling.
یا هرگونه احساسات سطح پایین باقی نمی‌ماند.
But if you pray to Shri Ganesha, also unauthorized
ولی اگر شما به شری‌گانشا دعا کنید و کمی هم به صورت غیرمجاز،
a little bit, that "Please make me innocent,
که: "لطفا مرا پاک گردانید،
so that I'm empowered to ask You for this boon,
طوری که برای درخواست این عطیه الهی قدرتمند گردم،
that wherever I go I become the source of innocence.
طوری که هر جا روم منشأ معصومیت شوم.
So that I emit innocence: when people look at me,
طوری که معصومیت را ساطع کنم. وقتی مردم به من نگاه می‌کنند،
they feel I am innocent."
احساس کنند که من معصوم هستم."
This is compassion,
این مهربانی است.
the compassion to ask Him to give you
مهربانی‌ای که از او بخواهید به شما،
the power of compassion itself.
خود قدرت مهربانی را عطا فرماید.
So that, as you see here these beautiful centers, as if
تا همان‌طور که شما اینجا این مراکز زیبا را می‌بینید،
the light starts moving horizontally;
گویی نور به شکل افقی شروع به حرکت می‌کند.
it starts moving on the sympathetic nervous system.
آن نور بر سیستم عصبی سمپاتیک شروع به حرکت می‌کند.
So you become the powerful innocence yourself.
پس شما خودتان آن معصوم قدرتمند می‌شوید.
You don't become stupid or childish,
شما نادان یا بچه نمی‌شوید،
but you become child-like.
بلکه همچون یک بچه می‌شوید.
The whole behavior is extremely dignified and innocent.
تمامی رفتارهای شما بی‌نهایت باوقار و پاک خواهد شد.
Normally if you find a person who is dignified,
معمولا اگر شما فرد باوقاری را ببینید،
is normally he’s not an innocent person,
معمولا آن شخص، فرد معصومی نیست،
because he puts up a show – it's a deliberation
چون‌ که او نمایش بازی می‌کند، او از عمد سعی می‌کند
to become serious and show that he’s very dignified,
که جدی باشد و نشان دهد که خیلی باوقار است،
to impress others.
تا دیگران را تحت تأثیر قرار دهد؛
And child doesn’t put up the show of innocence, of
و یک بچه، نمایش معصومیت،
of dignity or anything, because the child is not aware
وقار یا هر چیزی بازی نمی‌کند، چون بچه خبر از
of deliberations.
تعمدی کار کردن ندارد.
But you develop that rare combination of innocent dignity.
ولی شما آن ترکیب نادر معصومیت و وقار را به دست خواهید آورد.
Now the other quality of, say, Shri Ganesha starts
حالا ویژگی دیگر شری گانشا
expressing itself on horizontal level,
زمانی خود را در سطح افقی نشان می‌دهد
that you become discreet.
که شما فردی بابصیرت شوید.
But that is a power, I'm again say,
ولی آن بصیرت یک قدرت است، دوباره می‌گویم.
the power of discretion you develop.
قدرت بصیرت شما بیشتر می‌شود.
Now one must understand the difference between
حالا باید فرق بین
the power of discretion, and discretion itself.
قدرت بصیرت و خود بصیرت را فهمید.
So “the power” means it acts.
بنابراین قدرت یعنی، "آن قدرت" عمل می‌کند.
For example, you may not speak, but if you are
به ‌طور مثال ممکن است شما صحبتی نکنید،
but if you are standing somewhere
اما وقتی جایی ایستاده‌اید،
the discretion itself will act in the situation.
خود بصیرت، در آن موقعیت، وارد عمل می‌شود.
Like a Sahaja yogi, supposing is a good Sahaja yogi,
مثلا یک ساهاجایوگی، فرض کنیم یک ساهاجایوگی خوب،
is going in a train, and the train has an accident –
در حال سفر با قطار است و قطار دچار حادثه می‌شود،
mostly it will not have, but has – nobody will die.
بیشتر وقت‌ها دچار حادثه نخواهد شد، ولی حالا شده؛ کسی نخواهد مرد.
So you establish the discretion which is power itself,
پس شما بصیرتی را برقرار می‌سازید که خود، قدرت است
that acts by itself.
و به خودی خود عمل می‌‌کند.
You don't have to say that you act, it acts,
لازم نیست شما بگویید که دارید عمل می‌کنید، آن قدرت عمل می‌کند،
but you just become the vehicle,
ولی شما فقط وسیله خواهید شد،
a beautiful clean vehicle of that discretion.
وسیله‌ای زیبا و تمیز برای آن بصیرت.
Then you should believe,
پس از آن است که شما باید بدانید که
now you are spreading horizontally.
حالا دارید به شکل افقی رشد می‌کنید.
In the first era of Sahaja Yoga,
در اولین دوران ساهاجایوگا،
you needed to see Me in person.
لازم بود که مرا شخصا ببینید.
As we say in Sanskrit, a “dhyeya”: is the target.
به شکلی که در سانسکریت می‌گوییم، دْهی‌یِیا: هدف.
You wanted the target in front of you.
شما هدف را در مقابل خود می‌خواستید.
(But see, there’s no word in English!) Dhyeya:
ولی هیچ کلمه‌ای در انگلیسی نیست! دْهِیا؛
whatever is to be achieved.
آنچه که باید به دست آید.
(Because there’s no word in the English language, what to do?)
چون هیچ کلمه‌ای در زبان انگلیسی نیست چه می‌شود کرد؟
So now when you wanted that all the time,
پس یک زمانی دائم این را می‌خواستید
and you felt happy, secured, joyous
و از داشتن او در مقابل خود،
when you had that in person before you.
احساس خرسندی و امنیت و شادی می‌کردید.
Then in the second era, now,
بعد در دوره دوم، حالا،
you will not desire so much that Mother should be there –
شما خیلی آرزو ندارید که مادر حتما باشد،
you'll take it over from Me.
این مسئولیت را از دوش من برخواهید داشت.
This is the divine desire I'm telling you about,
این آرزوی خداوند است که دارم از آن صحبت می‌کنم
and you have to work on that from today onwards.
و شما باید روی آن از حالا کار کنید.
I am with you, you know that;
من با شما هستم، این را شما می‌دانید؛
but need not be in this body,
ولی لازم نیست در این بدن باشم،
because I don’t know if I exist in this body or not.
چون نمی‌دانم آیا در این بدن خواهم ماند یا نه.
But once this desire starts working,
ولی وقتی این آرزو شروع به کار کند،
you will see tremendous miracles happening.
شما معجزات بی‌شماری را خواهید دید که اتفاق می‌افتند.
When the child is born to a mother,
وقتی یک بچه از مادری به دنیا می‌آید،
automatically she gets milk.
به طور خودبه‌خود آن مادر شیر پیدا می‌کند.
So the nature is so connected with the whole thing.
بنابراین طبیعت بسیار با همه چیز در ارتباط است.
In your divine desire also it is connected.
به همین شکل آرزوی الهی شما نیز وصل است.
And it is very evident when you are a divine person.
و وقتی شما یک شخصی الهی باشید، این کاملا واضح است.
So you may find Me anywhere:
پس شاید شما مرا در هر جایی ببینید.
you are walking on the street,
دارید در خیابان قدم می‌زنید،
suddenly you might find Mataji walking with you.
یک مرتبه ماتاجی را خواهید دید که با شما قدم می‌زند.
So this is the second era we have started,
پس این دوران دوم است که ما آغاز کرده‌ایم
and you should not be shocked
شما نباید از دیدن من شوکه شوید
if you see Me sitting on your bed
که روی تختتان نشسته‌ام
and putting My hand on your head.
و دستم را روی سرتان گذاشته‌ام.
Or you may see Me in the form of Christ
یا ممکن است مرا به شکل مسیح ببینید
walking into your room,
که به اتاق شما قدم می‌گذارم
or as Shri Rama.
یا به شکل شری راما.
That has to happen,
این باید اتفاق بیفتد،
so you should be prepared.
پس شما باید آماده باشید!
Already so many miracles have taken place on you,
تاکنون معجزات بسیاری برای شما اتفاق افتاده است،
but on a grosser level.
ولی در یک سطح زمخت‌تر.
We have seen the light coming on My head,
شما نوری که بر سر من می‌آید را دیده‌اید
and the photographs have shown some miracles to you.
و عکس‌ها به شما معجزاتی را نشان داده‌اند.
But many things will happen,
ولی خیلی چیزها اتفاق خواهد افتاد،
that you will see something that you could never imagine.
که چیزهایی را خواهید دید که تصورش را نمی‌توانستید بکنید.
This has to happen, just to convince you
این باید اتفاق بیفتد، فقط برای این که شما را متقاعد کند
that you have reached a certain height of your evolution
که در این دوره جدید پراگیا لوک،
in the new area of Pragyalok.
به یک درجه از پیشرفت خود رسیده‌اید؛
Because this is a new state into which
چون این مرحله‌ای تازه است که
now you will be entering, on a horizontal basis.
اکنون به صورت افقی وارد آن خواهید شد.
In this area you will give up asking for gross things,
در این دوره جدید، شما دیگر برای چیزهایی زمخت، درخواست نخواهید داشت،
and also for anything subtler, anything that is subtle.
و نیز برای هر چیزی ظریف‌تر، هر چیزی که ظریف است.
The asking will disappear,
درخواست کردن ناپدید خواهد شد
and that is the time you’ll become very powerful.
و آن زمانی است که شما بسیار قدرتمند می‌شود.
Whatever I say happens, as you know;
و چنانچه می‌دانید، هر چه بگویم اتفاق خواهد افتاد؛
only thing, I cannot command you to be evolved.
تنها چیزی که نمی‌توانم به شما فرمان دهم آن است که متحول شوید.
The Kundalini's work in you has been done, quite a lot.
کار کندالینی در شما تا حد زیادی انجام شده است.
Now the new work of compassion,
حالا کار جدید مهرورزی،
of spreading it to others has to be done by you.
انتشار آن به دیگران باید توسط شما انجام شود.
As the light grows brighter and brighter,
هرچه که نور روشن و روشن‌تر ‌شود،
the area it covers becomes bigger and bigger.
ناحیه‌ای که تحت پوشش قرار می‌دهد، بزرگ و بزرگتر خواهد شد.
So you become the giver of compassion.
بنابراین شما عطا کننده محبت خواهید شد.
In My last lecture, which you have heard already,
در آخرین سخنرانی‌ام که شما قبلا شنیدید،
I have requested you how to do tapah.
از شما درخواست کردم که چطور ریاضت بکشید.
(Oh, I see, I’m sorry. All right.)
اوه، فهمیدم، ببخشید. باشد...
With a complete surrendered mind you have to go through
با ذهنی کاملا تسلیم، شما باید
the pilgrimage, say, of this castle.
زیارت این قصر را انجام دهید.
This is one of the glimpses of the tapah
این گوشه‌ای از ریاضت‌هایی است
that you have to do, because I am told
که شما باید بکشید، چون به من گفته شده
some of you had to get into little difficulties,
برخی از شما دچار مشکلات کوچکی شده‌اید
and you people suffered a little bit
و شما کمی در مسیر این زیارت
on your way for the pilgrimage.
سختی کشیده‌اید.
But it is fun to be venturesome and to get into places
ولی این اسباب تفریح است که ماجراجو باشیم و به جاهایی برویم
where the devils dare not go.
که شیطان جرأت ورود به آن را ندارد.
Fun: no word!
تفریح - هیچ کلمه‌ای نیست!
They have never fun! Let us see, it is miserable!
آنها هیچ وقت تفریح نمی‌کنند! بگذار بگوییم، این بدبختی است!
And if you know how to get fun out of the so-called
و اگر شما بدانید که چطور از این به اصطلاح
discomforts, then you should know
ناراحتی‌ها، اسباب تفریح فراهم کنید،
you are on the right lights.
باید بدانید که در مسیر درست هستید.
And as you start becoming discreet automatically,
و وقتی به طور خودبه‌خود فردی بابصیرت شوید،
you should know you are progressing well.
باید بدانید که دارید خوب پیشرفت می‌کنید.
As you become more peaceful and your temper
اگر می‌بینید که دارید بیشتر آرام می‌شوید
vanishes in the thin air as soon as you see somebody
و اگر کسی به شما حمله کرد،
attacking you, then know that you are progressing well.
عصبانیت شما سریعا محو می‌شود، پس بدانید که دارید خوب پیشرفت می‌کنید.
As soon as you see a ordeal or a calamity falling on
اگر به محض دیدن سختی یا مشقتی که بر شخص وارد می‌شود،
the personality and you do not get worried about it,
و شما نگران آن نمی‌شوید،
then know that you are progressing.
پس بدانید که دارید پیشرفت می‌کنید.
When no amount of artificiality can impress you,
وقتی ساختگی بودن به هر میزانی که باشد شما را تحت تاثیر خود قرار ندهد،
then know that you are progressing.
پس بدانید که دارید پیشرفت می‌‌کنید.
No amount of material well-being in others
اگر خوشبختی مادی دیگران به هر میزانی که باشد
makes you unhappy, no more unhappy,
شما را غمگین نکند، دیگر شما را غمگین نکند،
then know that you are progressing well.
بدانید که دارید خوب پیشرفت می‌کنید.
No amount of
هیچ میزانی از
labor or
کار و زحمت
or troubles are sufficient to become a Sahaja yogi.
برای تبدیل شدن به یک ساهاجایوگی، کافی نیست.
Any – whatever you may try, one cannot become a Sahaja yogi,
هر چقدر هم تلاش بکنید، نمی‌توانید یک ساهاجایوگی شوید،
while you have got it without any effort.
در حالی که شما آن را بدون هیچ تلاشی به دست آورده‌اید،
So you are something special.
پس شما فردی به خصوص هستید.
So this, once you understand that you are special,
بنابراین زمانی که شما متوجه این موضوع شوید ،که فردی خاص هستید
you will become humble about it.
تواضع پیشه می‌کنید.
Then when it happens to you that you’ve humbled down
بعد زمانی تواضع پیدا می‌کنید
when you see you have achieved something,
که ببینید دستاوردی داشته‌اید،
that you have some powers,
که قدرت‌هایی دارید،
that you are emitting innocence, that you are discreet,
که از خود پاکی منتشر می‌کنید، این که شما بابصیرت هستید
and as a result of that you become more compassion,
و در نتیجه فردی می‌شوید که مهربان‌تر،
humbler personality, a sweeter personality,
متواضع‌تر و شیرین‌تر است،
then you should believe
آن وقت باید ایمان بیاورید
that you are in the heart of your Mother.
که در قلب مادرتان هستید.
This is what is the sign of the new Sahaja yogi now
این علامت یک ساهاجایوگی جدید است، الان،
in the new era, who has to move with new force.
در دوره جدید، که با نیرویی جدید حرکت می‌کند.
Where you will grow so fast that without meditation,
جایی که شما بسیار سریع رشد خواهید کرد که بدون مدیتیشن،
you will be in meditation;
در مدیتیشن خواهید بود.
without being in My presence, you will be in My presence;
بدون آن که در حضور من باشید، در حضور من خواهید بود.
without asking, you will be blessed by your Father.
بدون درخواست، مورد رحمت پدرتان قرار خواهید گرفت.
This is what you are in for;
به خاطر همین اینجا هستید؛
and again I welcome you to this new era today,
و دوباره من ورود شما را به این دوره جدید، امروز،
on this great day of Sahasrara.
در این  روز عظیم سحسرارا خوش‌آمد می‌گویم.
May God bless you all.
رحمت خداوند شامل حال شما باشد.